Jerry Robinson Papers
Jerry Robinson Papers
1953-2009
Robinson, Jerry.
70 linear ft.
Correspondence and submissions from readers of True Classroom Flubs and Fluffs, original cartoon artwork for Jett Scott, Still Life and Flubs and Fluffs, proofs and research files.
149547
Biographical History
Jerry Robinson (1922- ) is an American comic book artist and cartoonist.
Robinson was born in Trenton, New Jersey in 1922 and studied journalism at Columbia University. Robinson is known for his work on Batman, which is where his career began in 1939 after meeting Bob Kane, creator of the then-new superhero. He has been credited with creating The Joker (whether alone or with Bill Finger and Bob Kane has been disputed) and assisting in the development Batman's sidekick, Robin the Boy Wonder.
During the 1940s and 1950s, Robinson also worked on comic books for Feature Comics, Harvey Comics and Marvel. He worked on The Green Hornet and tried his hand at an original superhero, Atoman for Spark Comics. Robinson also ghosted on Kerry Drake and the Lone Ranger. In 1953 Robinson launched his first newspaper strip, a science fiction piece entitled Jett Scott, which was syndicated by the New York Herald Tribune and lasted until 1955. He followed this with Still Life and a Sunday page for the New York Daily News entitled True Classroom Flubs and Fluffs (1964-1984). From 1977 to 1995, Robinson also produced Life with Robinson for the Chicago Tribune-New York News Syndicate.
Robinson has also written and illustrated books including The Comics: An Illustrated History of Comic Strip Art (1974). He has curated exhibitions in several countries and has been commissioned by the United Nations to produce exhibitions including a 2007-2008 exhibition for the 60th anniversary of the U.N.'s Universal Declaration of Human Rights.
Robinson has been active in many professional organizations. He served as president of the National Cartoonists Society and the Association of American Editorial Cartoonists. Robinson was involved in the overseas tours NCS organized to entertain military personnel. Robinson received the Milton Caniff Lifetime Achievement Award from NCS in 2002 and received awards for Best Comic Magazine Artist (1956), Best Special Feature (1966) and Best Syndicated Panel (1964). He founded and was president of the Cartoonists and Writer's Syndicate and was a board member for the International Museum of Cartoon Art. He has also received honors from the International Salon of Humor, International Pavilion of Humor in Montreal and at Comic-Con International in San Diego. He has also been involved with the Society of Illustrators and the Overseas Press Club and taught cartooning at the School of Visual Arts during the 1950s.
As of 2010, Jerry Robinson operated CartoonArts International and the Cartoonists & Writers Syndicate which included 550 artists from over 75 countries.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Jerry Robinson Papers are arranged in five series and contain correspondence from readers, artwork, printed material and research material.
Cartoons (1953-1970) contains original artwork, sketches, clippings and proofs of Robinson's newspaper comic strips and panel cartoons Still Life (Chicago Tribune-New York News Syndicate), Jett Scott (New York Herald-Tribune) and Flubs and Fluffs (New York Daily News). There are also preliminary pencil sketches for Jett Scott and Flubs and Fluffs. Robinson's 161 completed artworks were drawn in ink. The series includes proofs produced in both color and black and white.
Reader Suggestions (opened) and Reader Suggestions (unopened) comprise the bulk of this collection. These series contain submissions by readers of Flubs and Fluffs from 1965 to 1986. Children submitted many of these and some include drawings. One series contains letters that have been opened and the other series contains unopened letters. Some of the incoming mail appears to have was submitted in response to a newspaper advertisement offering ten dollars for the winning suggestion.
The Work Files series consists of research material used by Robinson for the revised edition of his book, The Comics: an Illustrated History of Comic Strip Art (originally published in 1974) as well as for the production of a cartoon calendar. The material includes photocopies and mockups with notes and commentary. Of particular interest are promotional information packets for comic strips popular in the 1990s and 2000s including: Baldo, Cathy, Jump Start, Family Tree, Garfield and Over the Hedge.
Miscellaneous (1953-1972) contains one item of biographical material, assorted printed material and correspondence that is unrelated to the Flubs and Fluffs submissions.
Arrangement of the Collection
Submissions that were unopened prior to donation have remained unopened. It has been sorted by postmark and foldered by month and/or year.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Robinson, Jerry.; New York Herald Tribune (Firm); Still life (cartoon); Daily news (New York, N.Y.: 1920); True Classroom Flubs and Fluffs (cartoon); Jett Scott (comic strip); American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Language and languages -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc.; Cartoons (humorous images); Comic strips.; Correspondence.; Fan mail.; Sketches.; Research notes.; Proofs (printed matter); Promotional materials.; Children's drawings.; Clippings (information artifacts); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jerry Robinson, 1967-1974, 2009-2010.
Inventory
- Cartoons
  - Jett Scott
    - Original artwork, Click here for a detailed inventory of daily and Sunday strips.
      - Daily strips, 1953-1955; 33 items 7" x 20 3/4" (Oversize 3)
      - Sketches, 1953-1955; multiple days on each board, months and days but no years; 71 items 14 1/4" x 22 ½" (Oversize 2)
      - Sunday strips, 1953-1955; 21 items 14 1/4" x 23" (Oversize 2)
    - Promotional and printed material, 1955 (Box 20)
    - Proofs (Sunday)
      - Black and white glossy, 1953-1955; 84 items (Oversize 1)
      - Black and white newsprint, 1953-1955; 55 items (Oversize 1)
      - Color newsprint, 1953-1955; 46 items (Oversize 1)
  - Still Life
    - Clippings, 1963-1964 Oct (Box 20)
    - Clippings, 1966 Jul-1967 Jun (Box 21)
    - Clippings, 1967; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Clippings, 1968; 9 folders (Box 22)
    - Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
    - Original artwork, 1963 Jun-1964 Jun; 1964 Aug; Click here for a detailed inventory. Items are also numbered on the back.; 6 3/4" x 8"; 80 items (Box 74)
  - True Classroom Flubs and Fluffs
    - Original artwork, 1965-1967; Click here for a detailed inventory.; 27 items 15" x 20" (Oversize 3)
    - Preliminary sketches, undated (Oversize 3)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 22)
- Reader suggestions (opened)
  - Flubs and Fluffs contributions
    - 1965-1968 (Box 1-20)
    - 1965, 8 folders (Box 22-23)
    - 1966, 19 folders (Box 23-24)
    - 1966-1969, undated, 11 folders (Box 81)
    - 1967, 53 folders (Box 24-28)
    - 1967-1969, undated, 19 folders (Box 78)
    - 1968, 59 folders (Box 28-33)
    - 1968, 1 folder (Box 75)
    - 1969, 61 folders (Box 33-37)
    - 1970, 52 folders (Box 38-41)
    - 1970, 1 folder (Box 75)
    - 1971, 42 folders (Box 42-45)
    - 1971, 1 folder (Box 75)
    - 1972, 55 folders (Box 45-49)
    - 1972, 1 folder (Box 75)
    - 1973, 33 folders (Box 49-51)
    - 1973, 1 folder (Box 75)
    - 1974, 9 folders (Box 51-53)
    - 1974-1979, 6 folders (Box 75)
    - 1983-1986, 4 folders (Box 76)
    - 1960s-1970s, 9 folders (Box 22)
    - Undated, 10 folders (Box 77)
    - Undated, 6 folders (Box 79)
- Reader suggestions (unopened)
  - Flubs and Fluffs contributions
    - 1966, 27 folders (Box 54-55)
    - 1966 Jul-Aug, 17 folders (Box 80)
    - 1967, 28 folders (Box 55-57)
    - 1968, 28 folders (Box 58-60)
    - 1969, 1 folders (Box 60)
    - 1972, 6 folders (Box 60)
    - 1973, 6 folders (Box 60-63)
    - 1974, 24 folders (Box 63-64)
    - 1975, 7 folders (Box 65)
    - 1976, 12 folders (Box 65-66)
    - 1977, 33 folders (Box 66-68)
    - 1978, 9 folders (Box 68)
    - 1983-1985, 8 folders (Box 68)
    - 1986, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - 1960s-1970s, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Undated, 12 folders (Box 69)
- Work files
  - Calendar, circa 1990s; 2 folders (Box 73)
  - Calendar, 1995-1997; 3 folders (Oversize 1)
  - Calendar data, 1997; 2 folders (Box 73)
  - Image scans, circa 2000s; 4 folders (Box 73)
  - Research, 1990s-2000s; 7 folders (Box 73)
  - Research, 1990s-2000s; 6 folders (Box 74)
  - Promotional packets for comic strips A-F, 1990s-2000s; 5 folders (Box 70)
  - Promotional packets for comic strips G-O, 1990s-2000s; 5 folders (Box 71)
  - Promotional packets for comic strips P-Z, 1990s-2000s; 5 folders (Box 72)
  - Used miscellaneous, 1997; 1 folder (Box 73)
- Miscellaneous
  - Biographical material, 1953 (Box 20)
  - Printed material, correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 22)